[
  {
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "What is a loop in programming? / ما هي الحلقات في البرمجة؟",
    "options": [
      "Fixing errors / إصلاح الأخطاء",
      "Moving sprites randomly / تحريك الشخصيات عشوائيًا",
      "Changing backgrounds / تغيير الخلفيات",
      "Repeating instructions / تكرار التعليمات"
    ],
    "answer": "Repeating instructions / تكرار التعليمات"
  },
  {
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Why are loops useful in games? / لماذا الحلقات مفيدة في الألعاب؟",
    "options": [
      "To move objects repeatedly / لتحريك الأشياء بشكل متكرر",
      "To make the game harder / لجعل اللعبة أصعب",
      "To stop the game / لإيقاف اللعبة",
      "To change the colors / لتغيير الألوان"
    ],
    "answer": "To move objects repeatedly / لتحريك الأشياء بشكل متكرر"
  },
  {
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which block would you use to make a sprite repeat an action 10 times? / أي مكعب يستخدم لجعل الشخصية تكرر فعلًا 10 مرات؟",
    "options": [
      "Forever",
      "If Touching",
      "Change x by 10",
      "Repeat 10"
    ],
    "answer": "Repeat 10"
  },
  {
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which block makes something happen forever? / أي مكعب يجعل الشيء يستمر إلى الأبد؟",
    "options": [
      "When Key Pressed",
      "Forever",
      "Change x by 10",
      "Repeat 10"
    ],
    "answer": "Forever"
  },
  {
    "type": "TF",
    "question": "A loop must always repeat forever / يجب أن تكرر الحلقة دائمًا إلى الأبد",
    "answer": "false"
  },
  {
    "type": "TF",
    "question": "The 'repeat until' loop will stop as soon as the condition becomes true | حلقة 'تكرار حتى' تتوقف بمجرد أن تصبح الحالة صحيحة",
    "answer": "true"
  },
  {
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "What happens if a 'repeat until' condition is never true? | ماذا يحدث إذا لم تتحقق حالة 'تكرار حتى' أبدًا؟",
    "options": [
      "The loop runs forever | تعمل الحلقة إلى الأبد",
      "The loop runs once | تعمل الحلقة مرة واحدة",
      "The loop doesn’t run at all | لا تعمل الحلقة أبدًا",
      "The program stops immediately | يتوقف البرنامج فورًا"
    ],
    "answer": "The loop runs forever | تعمل الحلقة إلى الأبد"
  },
  {
      "type": "TF",
      "question": "Loops help repeat actions without writing the same block again / تساعد الحلقات في تكرار الأفعال دون كتابة نفس المكعب مرة أخرى",
      "answer": "true"
  },
    {
      "type": "TF",
      "question": "The following block repeats an action forever 'Repeat 10' المكعب التالي يكرر الفعل للأبد",
      "answer": "false"
    },
    {
      "type": "TF",
      "question": "The following block repeat actions only once 'Forever' المكعب التالي ينفذ الأوامر مرة واحدة فقط",
      "answer": "false"
    },
    {
      "type": "TF",
      "question": "Loops are used only in games / تُستخدم الحلقات فقط في الألعاب",
      "answer": "false"
    }
]